<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
	<game id="754">
		<path>./Alex Kidd in Miracle World (UEB) (V1.1) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Alex Kidd in Miracle World</name>
		<desc>Many centuries ago, on the planet Aries, there lived a boy called Alex Kidd. For seven years, he lived on Mt. Eternal studying Shellcore, an ancient art that makes one strong enough to break rocks into pieces. As he was leaving the mountain one day to travel to his spiritual homeland, a dying man told him that the peaceful city of Radactian was in grave danger. Before taking his last breath, the man gave Alex a piece of a map and a medallion made of Sun Stone.

There are eleven locations in which Alex must explore, each of them has its own unique dangers. In each location, Alex can collect bags of coins, which can be used to buy items at the shop and are used to help Alex get through each location (eg: motorcycle, peticopter, power bracelet, etc.) There are also traps that Alex must avoid like the ghost that chases him. He can also collect the Telepathy Ball that will help him read people's minds.

Later, Alex learns that in order to save Radactian from destruction, he must first defeat Janken the Great, Emperor of the planet Janbarik (he got his name from his expertise at the game of Janken -- or what people call "scissors, paper, stone" in the Western World. Janken has sent his henceman all over Radactian to prepare the game for Alex as he passes by them. In order to get past them, Alex must win three times at Janken. If he loses, he is turned to stone and vanished from Radactian forever. Later on in the game, Alex must play with the same henceman, but only this time, when Alex wins, they decide to play dirty.

Alex uses his fists to wipe out some of Janken's enemies such as birds, sea horses, bats, monkeys, frogs, and a few others. If his quest to save Radactian from the evil hands of Janken becomes difficult, he can instead use the power bracelet to perform the "Shocking Waves of Destruction", an ancient trick in the art of Shellcore.

Before Alex comes face-to-face with Janken, he should rescue his brother, Egle, from imprisonment, and get the letter and two medallions.</desc>
		<image>./images/Alex Kidd in Miracle World (UEB) (V1.1) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Alex Kidd in Miracle World (UEB) (V1.1) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Alex Kidd in Miracle World (UEB) (V1.1) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Alex Kidd in Miracle World (UEB) (V1.1) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19861201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform / Run &amp; Jump</genre>
		<family>Alex Kidd</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>f43e74ffec58ddf62f0b8667d31f22c0</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051142" />
	</game>
	<game id="778">
		<path>./Alex Kidd in Shinobi World (UEB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Alex Kidd in Shinobi World</name>
		<desc>Alex Kidd continues his adventures in Alex Kidd in Shinobi World, featuring remixes of the music you heard from Shinobi, and featuring the common enemy: Ninjas.

The Dark Ninja, whom was banished 10,000 years ago, has returned to rule Miracle World. He also takes young Alex's girlfriend and use her as a sacrifice. To help Alex defeat the Dark Ninja and rescue his girlfriend, a god enters Alex's body, causing Alex to become a ninja master.

There are four rounds, with three levels each, and has Alex travel through locations like office blocks, construction sites, shipyards, and jungles. He must go through each level defeating ninjas and other wildlife. In the last levels, he must defeat bosses including Kabuto, Heli, Robster, and Hanzo. To survive some levels, you must learn the secret jumping technique, described on page eight of the game's instruction manual. You start the game with three lives and are presented with an energy bar with three units, but you'll lose one if an enemy touches you. Furthermore, If you lose all three energy units, you lose a life, and if you lose all three lives, the game is over.

Additional energy units can be obtained by collecting hearts that can be found by breaking treasure chests. The maximum units you can get is six. From there, the heart is replaced by a mini-Alex. Collect this and you've earned yourself an extra life. You'll get hearts if you have less than six units. 

You can also get weapons like spears and power swords by breaking these treasure cheats. However, if you're lucky, you can obtain a Tornado icon, letting you transform into a tornado while mini-Tornados whirl around the screen, seeking enemies. This allows you to either go left or right so your enemies get sucked in and are knocked out.</desc>
		<image>./images/Alex Kidd in Shinobi World (UEB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Alex Kidd in Shinobi World (UEB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Alex Kidd in Shinobi World (UEB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Alex Kidd in Shinobi World (UEB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.65</rating>
		<releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<family>Alex Kidd</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>d62b631506913712a2103f54912458a5</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051147" />
	</game>
	<game id="852">
		<path>./Alien Syndrome (UEB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Alien Syndrome</name>
		<desc>Alien Syndrome is a scrolling shooter arcade conversion.

Your job is to run around and rescue all the captives and make it to the escape hatch before the time bomb explodes. Then face the mother alien at the end of the level.

You can play as a single player or two people, taking turns. (Player 2 starts the game after Player 1 dies and vice versa.)</desc>
		<image>./images/Alien Syndrome (UEB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Alien Syndrome (UEB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Alien Syndrome (UEB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Alien Syndrome (UEB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sanritsu Denki</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter / Run and Gun</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
		<md5>197cba1894218cbe54752f58da477869</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051152" />
	</game>
	<game id="769">
		<path>./Asterix (EB) (V1.0) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Astérix</name>
		<desc>Getafix, the Druid whose potion has kept his village from falling in Caesar's hands, has been kidnapped! Join Asterix and Obelix as they try to rescue the druid and save the village!</desc>
		<image>./images/Asterix (EB) (V1.0) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Asterix (EB) (V1.0) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Asterix (EB) (V1.0) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Asterix (EB) (V1.0) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19920401T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<family>Astérix</family>
		<players>1-2</players>
		<md5>0feb52e9b0a8cd378fb38902eb4b4100</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051157" />
	</game>
	<game id="918">
		<path>./Astro Warrior (JUB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Astro Warrior</name>
		<desc>Basic Sega shoot-em-up in which you must guide your ship through three zones while avoiding hazards. Your only weapon are bullets as your only defense, but if you shoot the flashing red pieces on the terrain, chances are that a green ship will approach you, and if you collect this ship, your weapons will be upgraded so that you shoot a laser beam instead. Keep collecting ships and you can shoot up to three laser beams at once. 

At the end of each zone, you will come across a boss that takes multiple hits to kill. If you manage to conquer all three zones, you are back to where you started. The whole point of this game is to earn as many points you can without losing all of your lives.</desc>
		<image>./images/Astro Warrior (JUB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Astro Warrior (JUB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Astro Warrior (JUB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Astro Warrior (JUB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Shoot'em Up / Vertical</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
		<md5>e645faa5628caab5129383fdbf4df090</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051203" />
	</game>
	<game id="962">
		<path>./Bank Panic (E) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Bank Panic</name>
		<desc>Bandits are holding up a bank and have taken people hostage, and as a gunslinger, it's your job to shoot them. The bank has 12 doors, and the bandits are behind each one of them. When they pull a gun out at you when you open a door, you have only a few seconds to shoot them before they shoot you. If you shoot them too early (ie: before he sticks his gun out at you), it is considered unfair, and you won't score any points, but if you're too late, he'll shoot you and you lose one of your three lives.If you waste too much time, a bandit will come out from one of the doors and stick dynamite on it. You must then shoot the dynamite to get rid of it. 

If you're lucky, either a man or a woman will throw you a bag of gold coins. If you shoot any of these people by accident, you also lose a life. More often than not, the person will throw his/her hands up, saying "I haven't got anything". That's when they will be replaced by bandits. 

Some men will carry three to five pieces of gold on top of their heads, and shooting at all of the gold will award you with a bag of gold coins. Others will be tied up with rope. If you shoot the rope, there's more money for you, because not only will you receive one bag of gold coins, but you'll get three bags of gold coins.

There are more than ten rounds in Bank Panic, and each one ends when a person behind all 12 doors was able to throw you a bag of gold coins. The rounds get difficult the further you get. For example, in later rounds, a few bandits will block your shot, and you have to then shoot twice. Also, regardless of what round you're on, you can shoot so many bandits before time runs out.</desc>
		<image>./images/Bank Panic (E) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Bank Panic (E) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Bank Panic (E) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Bank Panic (E) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.65</rating>
		<releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sanritsu Denki</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter / FPV</genre>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>da53d18840d3197313155c85ffde9871</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<region>eu</region>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051208" />
	</game>
	<game id="840">
		<path>./California Games (UEB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>California Games</name>
		<desc>California Games was the original "Extreme Games" – what today's generation might call "X-Games in the sun".  Players can select sponsors (absent in some versions) and compete in events such as skateboarding, footbag, surfing, roller skating, flying disc (frisbee) and BMX.  The surfing event is ranked by judges, which give a score to help the players improve their routine.

The Atari versions (2600 and Lynx) of the game omit the flying disc and roller skating events, while the Genesis version omits only the flying disc event.</desc>
		<image>./images/California Games (UEB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/California Games (UEB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/California Games (UEB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/California Games (UEB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19890501T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Epyx</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Sports / Multisports</genre>
		<family>California Games</family>
		<players>1-8</players>
		<md5>182b179a1226fb5b1e1cf6bb2f351c50</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051213" />
	</game>
	<game id="18473">
		<path>./Chapolim x Dracula - Um Duelo Assustador (B) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Chapolim X Drácula - Um Duelo Assustador</name>
		<desc>Vampires' population in Transilvania has increased a lot lately, and there's not enough human blood to feed them all. To solve this demographic problem comes Chapolim!

Chapolim X Drácula: Um Duelo Assustador (which translates Chapolim vs. Dracula: A Frightening Duel) is an authorized "hack" of Ghost House, with Ghost House's hero, Mick, replaced by Chapolim (or El Chapulín Colorado in original Spanish), a famous Mexican character from a TV series. Chapolim is a parody to superheroes in general. He dresses a red grasshopper costume with a yellow heart in the chest with the leters "CH". He also usually carries his Marreta Biônica (Chipote Chillón in the original, Squeaky Mallet in English) a red (toy) hammer.

At each stage, Chapolim must defeat five vampires that are in torpor within their coffins. The coffins are locked, so he must first find the keys to unlock them. He'll find the keys killing the most diverse enemies that haunt the mansion he's in, such as ghosts, bats, fire blowers, mummies, etc. Once he's got a key, he must unlock a coffin and then defeat the vampire who sleeps there.

In order to kill his enemies, Chapolim can jump over them or punch them. Every once in a while, his Marreta Biônica will come flying from one side of the screen to another, and if he jumps over it, he'll catch it. Chapolim can also punch the lights of the mansion: they'll flash and paralyze his enemies.

Chapolim starts with 3 lives and no continues. He'll be healed by collecting treasures through the castle, and will gain additional lives at every 50,000 and 150,000 points.

All the text in the game is in Portuguese.</desc>
		<video>./videos/Chapolim x Dracula - Um Duelo Assustador (B) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<thumbnail>./images/Chapolim x Dracula - Um Duelo Assustador (B) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.45</rating>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>Tectoy</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
		<md5>2c709ba8cdc3a1b7adc5bc838eabf6f3</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T060138" />
	</game>
	<game id="44244">
		<path>./Comical Machine Gun Joe (Japan).sms</path>
		<name>Comical Machine Gun Joe</name>
		<desc>This game was originally released only in Japan on Sega Card, though has appeared in several compilations since.</desc>
		<image>./images/Comical Machine Gun Joe (Japan)-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Comical Machine Gun Joe (Japan)-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Comical Machine Gun Joe (Japan)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Comical Machine Gun Joe (Japan)-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<releasedate>19860421T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>1</players>
		<playcount>2</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20250811T152938</lastplayed>
		<md5>2d59b3d27f022b04a597e767e6660ca9</md5>
		<gametime>1664</gametime>
		<lang>jp</lang>
		<region>jp</region>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051230" />
	</game>
	<game id="779">
		<path>./Deep Duck Trouble Starring Donald Duck (EB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Deep Duck Trouble Starring Donald Duck</name>
		<desc>Donald meets Hewey, Dewey and Louie, back from their latest adventure with Uncle Scrooge.  But Uncle Scrooge has been cursed by a pendant he found while adventuring, and is now floating in the air like a balloon!  He gives Donald his adventurer's diary and asks Donald to retrace his steps and return the pendant to its rightful place - this is the only thing that will return Scrooge to normal.

Deep Duck Trouble is a platform game where you play as Donald Duck.  You must make your way through four different areas of the island - the jungle, an inlet, a volcano, and a valley - and defeat bosses at the end of each area.  Donald can defeat enemies by jumping on their heads.  He can also defeat them by kicking bricks which will may then hit his enemies.  Donald's trademark temper also comes into play: if he eats a chili pepper, he will become furious and plough through anything in his way, whether it be bricks or enemies!</desc>
		<image>./images/Deep Duck Trouble Starring Donald Duck (EB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Deep Duck Trouble Starring Donald Duck (EB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Deep Duck Trouble Starring Donald Duck (EB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Deep Duck Trouble Starring Donald Duck (EB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<family>Disney</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>05e3071aad9c36b6e18f1656592eeb3d</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051235" />
	</game>
	<game id="801">
		<path>./Fantasy Zone (JUE) (V1.2) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Fantasy Zone</name>
		<desc>The Fantasy Zone is a solar system consisting of eight brightly colored, fantastic planets. The evil Menons are trying to take over all of the planets in the Fantasy Zone by using misappropriated foreign currency to build their forces. It is the player's job to recover all of the coins and save the solar system! 

Fantasy Zone is an arcade style shooter for one or two players. The goal is to destroy all of the creatures on each planet and collect as many of the lost coins as possible. At the end of each level is a large enemy that will have to be defeated before moving on to the next world.  At various points in the game, the player will be able to find a parts shop, which allows purchasing improvements for his spaceship, including better weapons and faster engines.</desc>
		<image>./images/Fantasy Zone (JUE) (V1.2) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Fantasy Zone (JUE) (V1.2) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Fantasy Zone (JUE) (V1.2) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Fantasy Zone (JUE) (V1.2) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19860901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Shoot'em Up / Horizontal</genre>
		<family>Fantasy Zone</family>
		<players>1-2</players>
		<md5>fed8690ee5fb895c09caa8e2b879ebd6</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051241" />
	</game>
	<game id="876">
		<path>./Gain Ground (EB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Gain Ground</name>
		<desc>Gain Ground is an arcade style action game with a bit of strategy thrown in. The goal is get all of the soldiers to the opposite side of the screen or to kill all of the enemies. Each soldier in the army has a unique specialization, from among 20 types. Each soldier can attack in two different ways, using either a normal weapon or a special weapon. The strategy comes from deciding which soldier would do best in which situation. Some weapons are better at dealing with certain enemies and obstacles than other weapons.

Players start with only three soldiers but can encounter other soldiers that can be rescued, by touching them. If the new solider survives long enough to reach the exit, they can be added to the soldier inventory. The number of possible soldier in a player's army is over 30 soldiers. There are 50 stages total, divided into rounds of 10. At the end of each round, players encounter an enemy boss.</desc>
		<image>./images/Gain Ground (EB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Gain Ground (EB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Gain Ground (EB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Gain Ground (EB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
		<md5>7d54230748fa41bb62b6f08e5dcede08</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051246" />
	</game>
	<game id="794">
		<path>./Golden Axe Warrior (UEB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Golden Axe Warrior</name>
		<desc>Golden Axe Warrior is a spin-off of the Golden Axe games, a series of side-scrolling Beat'Em Ups from Sega.
 
In ancient times a horde of giants rebelled against the elders and a brutal war ensued. Things looked grave until finally a hero, carrying the Golden Axe, appeared and drove back the giants. Since then, the kingdom of Firewood has been ruled by a family that had mastered the power of the nine crystals to ward off all evil from Firewood. Everyone lived in peace until one of Firewood's ministers betrayed his king and sold the nine crystals to Death Adder, one of the evil giants. Death Adder has hidden the nine crystals in nine dungeons, has unleashed hordes of monsters and is threatening to take over the world. Will there be another hero who can find the Golden Axe and defeat Death Adder?

Gameplay in Golden Axe Warrior is very similar to The Legend Of Zelda, meaning you will spend most of your time exploring the large overworld fighting against lots of enemies and looking for the dungeons in which the crystals are hidden. Inside the dungeons you have to fight more enemies, find treasures and keys, solve simple puzzles and defeat the dungeon's boss to get one of the crystals. In order to survive against the large number of enemies, you will be able to find many different weapons and three different spells.</desc>
		<image>./images/Golden Axe Warrior (UEB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Golden Axe Warrior (UEB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Golden Axe Warrior (UEB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Golden Axe Warrior (UEB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19910401T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Role Playing Game</genre>
		<family>Golden Axe</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>d46e40bbb729ba233f171ad7bf6169f5</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051252" />
	</game>
	<game id="786">
		<path>./Jungle Book, The (Europe).sms</path>
		<name>The Jungle Book</name>
		<desc>This 8-bit adaptation of Disney's 1967 animated film Jungle Book is slightly different from the other versions. Although most of the main elements remain the same, the most noticeable differences are in level design and some missing items.

The player controls Mowgli in his journey to the human village. Mowgli will swing on and climb vines, run and jump while facing enemies such as coconut-throwing monkeys, snakes and vampire bats. To fight them, Mowgli can throw bananas in eight directions. He'll also find upgrades and weapons such as boomerangs inside banana bunches. There are some boss fights with main characters of the movie, such as the snake Kaa.

The objective of each of the 10 time-limited levels (or "scenes") is to collect gems scattered around them. Collecting certain amounts of gems grant access to bonus levels. The player starts the game with 4 lives and 1 continue.</desc>
		<image>./images/Jungle Book, The (Europe)-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Jungle Book, The (Europe)-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Jungle Book, The (Europe)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Jungle Book, The (Europe)-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.65</rating>
		<releasedate>19931201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Syrox Developments</developer>
		<publisher>Virgin Interactive Entertainment</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>ed224898befb4fb246175e46f9982821</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<region>eu</region>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051258" />
	</game>
	<game id="782">
		<path>./Jurassic Park (EB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Jurassic Park</name>
		<desc>One of many games based on the 1993 blockbuster Jurassic Park, the version for Sega's 8-bit systems combines side-scrolling shooting action and platforming levels.

In each of the five stages of the game, one escaped dinosaur species must be recaptured. Each level begins with a side-scrolling driving section. Dinosaurs attack the car and must be fend off by firing at them with a crosshair. If the player survives long enough, a boss battle against an especially powerful dinosaur follows.

After the completion of the driving section the level continues with a platform section. The player must jump, duck and climb to survive moving lifts, floors that will crumble under his feet, environmental hazards like acid drops, steam leaks or giant boulders and more. Dinosaurs will of course also stand in the way, but can be defeated by using several weapons: a rifle, a grenade launcher and hand grenades. Navigating the often maze-like levels will lead to the dinosaur that must be captured and a corresponding boss fight.

The first four levels (featuring a Velociraptor, Pteranodon, Triceratops and Brachiosaurus) can be tackled in any order, but the final level, featuring the Tyrannosaurus Rex, is only unlocked when the others have been completed.</desc>
		<image>./images/Jurassic Park (EB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Jurassic Park (EB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Jurassic Park (EB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Jurassic Park (EB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<family>Jurassic Park</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>b05014defe8d0c3d0ad6f67851ca15d7</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051301" />
	</game>
	<game id="822">
		<path>./Kenseiden (UEB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Kenseiden</name>
		<desc>In Kenseiden, you play Hayato, a fearless samurai warrior. You must get back the stolen swords and scrolls, and defeat the evil waiting in the Black Castle!

Kenseiden is a one-player game that comprises of sixteen levels. Each of the levels are side-scrolling, with bamboo houses or dank, haunted caves as their backdrop. These levels see Hayato beseigned by ghosts, skeletons, and other spirits of the supernatural. On his side is his curved sword, which he can swish at will against the monsters. If Hayato comes in contact with a monster, he will lose some life.

At the end of each level, you will have to fight a warlock or one of their henchmen. More often than not, there is a hut with a sealed door, but the door is not unlocked unless a warlock or henceman is defeated. You gain a new special power whenever you recover a scroll from them. These special powers range from high jumping to the ability to whirl your sword around like a windmill.</desc>
		<image>./images/Kenseiden (UEB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Kenseiden (UEB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Kenseiden (UEB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Kenseiden (UEB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19880901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>93dbdbe850b4a7db2142b861f8005716</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051306" />
	</game>
	<game id="809">
		<path>./Master of Darkness (EB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Master of Darkness</name>
		<desc>Master of Darkness is a Platformer very similar to Castlevania.

You play as a psychologist trying to defeat Dracula. This requires you to fight your way through several spooky locations such as cemeteries, laboratories, castles or a house of wax dolls. To defeat your enemies, you can use several primary and secondary weapons. Primary weapons are close combat weapons ranging from knifes to rapiers and axes, that differ in range and efficiency. Secondary weapons are long-range weapons (pistols, bombs etc.) with limited ammunition. The game features 5 Rounds divided into 3 stages. At the end of each stage, a boss must be defeated.</desc>
		<image>./images/Master of Darkness (EB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Master of Darkness (EB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Master of Darkness (EB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Master of Darkness (EB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19930501T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sims</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>8354932a7f20e84a808471b3724a56f8</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051311" />
	</game>
	<game id="870">
		<path>./OutRun (UJEB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Out Run</name>
		<desc>Race across varied terrain in this conversion of one of the most famous arcade racing games. Your Ferrari is at the ready, complete with female passenger, over a series of short tracks.

Gameplay is viewed form just above and behind the car, so you can see it. The roads are full of sharp bends and hazards, contact with which can cause the car to roll and lose you time. On each section of track there is a fork in the road, allowing you to choose which direction you go in. You have to complete 5 track sections in total, out of the 15 in the game.</desc>
		<image>./images/OutRun (UJEB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/OutRun (UJEB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/OutRun (UJEB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/OutRun (UJEB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19871001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA AM2</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Racing, Driving</genre>
		<family>OutRun</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>28d1ee4dc0d20b672cdce39d82ab862d</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051316" />
	</game>
	<game id="865">
		<path>./Paperboy (UB) (V1.1) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Paperboy</name>
		<desc>Based on the arcade game, the object of Paperboy is to deliver papers to your customers while inflicting as much damage as possible to the houses of your non-customers. To make things more difficult, numerous obstacles get in your way including construction workers, rogue tires, skateboarders, dogs and cats, cars, and even the occasional tornado.</desc>
		<image>./images/Paperboy (UB) (V1.1) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Paperboy (UB) (V1.1) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Paperboy (UB) (V1.1) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Paperboy (UB) (V1.1) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.6</rating>
		<releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Tiertex</developer>
		<publisher>U.S. Gold</publisher>
		<genre>Sports / Cycling</genre>
		<family>Paperboy</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>9b694d765038ffb87b36174412452588</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051322" />
	</game>
	<game id="768">
		<path>./Phantasy Star (UE) (V1.2) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Phantasy Star</name>
		<desc>Alis is a young girl whose brother Nero was brutally killed by a mysterious man known as Lassic. Nero's last words were: "Sister, find a warrior named Odin, he can help you to defeat Lassic!" Now Alis' dangerous adventure begins. Her first task is to find Odin. Then, with help and support from her friends, Alis will have to stop the evil Lassic and save the world...

This game is the very first installment in the long-lived Phantasy Star series. It is a futuristic RPG that uses a turn-based combat system (viewed from first-person perspective). An unusual feature of this game is that some locations are also viewed from first-person perspective. You can explore those locations by moving forward or backward, and the environments are in pseudo-3D.</desc>
		<image>./images/Phantasy Star (UE) (V1.2) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Phantasy Star (UE) (V1.2) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Phantasy Star (UE) (V1.2) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Phantasy Star (UE) (V1.2) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Role Playing Game</genre>
		<family>Phantasy Star</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>1110938df80f4e44c8213d7f85cfb5e6</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<region>eu</region>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051328" />
	</game>
	<game id="913">
		<path>./Pit Fighter (E) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Pit Fighter</name>
		<desc>Pit-Fighter is a 3rd-person fight game that features digitized graphics of real fighters and zooming effects.  Players select one of three fighters (Buzz, Ty or Kato) to take on anyone who dares. At the conclusion of a match, players are individually awarded a Knockout Bonus, Brutality Bonus, and a Fight Purse. Every third match is a Grudge Match where players test the skills of each other. The last man standing is the winner of this three-knockdown match. Players fight their way to the Elimination Match to decide who wins the opportunity to dethrone the champion, the Masked Warrior.</desc>
		<image>./images/Pit Fighter (E) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Pit Fighter (E) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Pit Fighter (E) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Pit Fighter (E) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.3</rating>
		<releasedate>19921201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>The Kremlin</developer>
		<publisher>Domark</publisher>
		<genre>Fighting</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
		<md5>585aed13ba548d0258a457cd6768511b</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<region>eu</region>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051333" />
	</game>
	<game id="806">
		<path>./Prince of Persia (Europe).sms</path>
		<name>Prince of Persia</name>
		<desc>The Grand Vizier Jaffar has thrown you into a dark dungeon and plans to marry the girl of your dreams in an hour. You're not going to let that happen are you? Try to escape from the dungeon, take out Jaffar's guards, find your way through the Sultan's palace and defeat Jaffar himself. Now go, you've got 60 minutes!

Prince of Persia is a 2D platformer with run and jump gameplay. Your hero must avoid deadly traps, solve some simple puzzles and engage in sword fights with the guards. The player has an infinite amount of lives, but has to restart at the beginning of a level each time he dies, and must complete the game within an hour. An especially noteworthy aspect of the game is the very fluent animation of your character.

The Game Boy Color and SNES versions of the game feature additional levels and new enemies. The Genesis version has a new intro and an altered set of graphics but the level layout remains almost identical to that of the original.</desc>
		<image>./images/Prince of Persia (Europe)-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Prince of Persia (Europe)-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Prince of Persia (Europe)-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Prince of Persia (Europe)-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19921001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Domark</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<family>Prince of Persia</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>70e9b330dd6a91e7310f3c8d9a934ecc</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<region>eu</region>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051338" />
	</game>
	<game id="814">
		<path>./R-Type (JUEB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>R-Type</name>
		<desc>R-Type is a side scrolling shoot 'em up best known for its extremely tough and strategic gameplay.  You control the R-9 spaceship as it launches a last-ditch effort to repel the evil Bydo empire.

The R-9 comes equipped as standard with a small gun which can only take down the smallest of enemies without firing several shots. By holding down the fire button, it can be loaded up so as to release a large burst of energy, eliminating all but the strongest enemies in its path. From time to time, pods will come flying in your direction. Upon being shot, they release an upgrade. The first one will invariably be the one called "The Force", which is a weapons pod that clings either to the front or the back of your ship, absorbing any enemy bullets or acting as a bumper with which you can fly head-on into them. You can also use it as an offensive weapon by firing it and pulling it back in. Mastering the Force is vital to surviving in R-Type, since it must be used both as protection against bullet clusters, as a remote controlled cannon, and in order to clear the screen from obstacles. Other upgrades give you target-seeking missiles or a bigger main gun. Different gun types, differentiated by their colour, serve different purposes. The blue one sends laser beams bouncing across the screen (good for tunnels), the red one fires straight ahead, and the yellow one follows any walls it may encounter (good for artillery emplacements).

The stages of R-Type are made in an organic style, certainly inspired by H. R. Giger's artwork for the Alien movies. When it came out, it was considered trend-setting since it broke off from the stereotypical sci-fi mould of other shoot'em'ups. In part, the levels themselves are your enemy, which is exemplified by the fourth, where spider-like creatures weave webs that cover the screen and block your path, or levels with intricate tunnel systems. Still, the levels are best handled with a combination of strategy and reflexes, without the memorisation that is required of R-Type's contemporary rival, Gradius.</desc>
		<image>./images/R-Type (JUEB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/R-Type (JUEB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/R-Type (JUEB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/R-Type (JUEB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19881201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Compile</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Shoot'em Up / Horizontal</genre>
		<family>R-Type</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>9e5507d51ac6f24c702a52a7abce0d3c</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051343" />
	</game>
	<game id="839">
		<path>./Rastan (UEB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Rastan</name>
		<desc>Rastan features five levels or hacking and slashing gameplay with a boss at the end of each level. Numerous enemies assault you on your journey such as flying demons, chimeras, valkyries, piranhas, skeleton undead and more. Fight through to the end and save the land of Lograth from certain doom.

The game features different weapons such axes, maces and fire swords, each with its own attributes like extended range or attack power. Armour can also be picked up in the forms shields, cloaks and armour, reducing the damage from enemy attacks. Other items include rings (increase the speed of your weapon) and jewelery for bonus points.</desc>
		<image>./images/Rastan (UEB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Rastan (UEB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Rastan (UEB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Rastan (UEB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19890401T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito</developer>
		<publisher>Taito</publisher>
		<genre>Platform / Fighter Scrolling</genre>
		<family>Rastan</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>5b3a785de403c311db7f17eae27caae6</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051349" />
	</game>
	<game id="892">
		<path>./Road Rash (EB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Road Rash</name>
		<desc>Road Rash is an aggressive motorcycle racing game where the player assumes the role of a biker who takes part in a series of illegal races across the U.S.A. Starting at the back of the pack the objective is always to finish first on a linear course, overtaking the other bikers. This is achieved by driving very well or by playing it dirty, knocking opponents of their bikes using clubs, crowbars or your bare hands. The other racers fight back in a similar fashion and there are also hazards. All the races take place on the regular road with normal traffic and the cops, as well as occasional oil slicks and stray cows.

By winning races you can get promoted to a stronger division and earn cash with which you can buy a better bike. Whenever you're knocked off your bike or hit something you will have to run back to your bike and lose valuable time, plus your bike will suffer some damage.</desc>
		<image>./images/Road Rash (EB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Road Rash (EB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Road Rash (EB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Road Rash (EB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19940301T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Probe Software</developer>
		<publisher>U.S. Gold</publisher>
		<genre>Racing, Driving / Motorcycle race TPV</genre>
		<family>Road Rash</family>
		<players>1-2</players>
		<md5>325575374d2db3755f83bba728990ebe</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051355" />
	</game>
	<game id="792">
		<path>./Simpsons, The - Bart vs. the Space Mutants (EB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Simpsons - Bart Vs The Space Mutants, The</name>
		<desc>Bart vs. The Space Mutants is a platform game where the player goes into the role of Bart Simpson (from the TV show The Simpsons) and must stop the Space Mutants from invading Springfield.

On each of the five levels, Bart must collect (or get rid of) the ingredients that the Space Mutants are planning to use to build their machine, such as purple objects or balloons. He also has to collect enough "proof" of the aliens existence (brown coins left behind when they are jumped on), so his family members will help him when he meets a boss (characters such as Nelson and Sideshow Bob). This won't be easy since the Space Mutants are "using" human bodies as disguise. In order to discover who are the real Space Mutants, Bart must use his X-ray Specs.

The ways Bart can get rid of those objects sought by the Space Mutants are numerous. For instance, in the first stage, Bart must get rid of purple objects. He can dye them red, cover them, wash them, etc. Some even involve a little puzzle solving, like playing a trick on Moe to make him get out of the bar.

Bart also has some coins that can be used in many ways throughout the game, like buying things, getting devices operating, etc. Those coins are essential to solve some puzzles in the game.</desc>
		<image>./images/Simpsons, The - Bart vs. the Space Mutants (EB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Simpsons, The - Bart vs. the Space Mutants (EB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Simpsons, The - Bart vs. the Space Mutants (EB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Simpsons, The - Bart vs. the Space Mutants (EB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Arc Developments</developer>
		<publisher>Flying Edge</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<family>The Simpsons</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>26df4404950cb8da47235833c0c101c6</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051400" />
	</game>
	<game id="775">
		<path>./Sonic Chaos (EB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Sonic Chaos</name>
		<desc>The inhabitants of South Island are in danger! Dr. Robotnik has stolen all the Chaos Emeralds which kept the power balance. Robotnik has thrown the Emeralds in a parallel universe and is keeping the red one. Sonic and Tail must retreive all the Chaos Emeralds before the destruction of South Island.
This is the first Game Gear game where you can play either Sonic or Tail.</desc>
		<image>./images/Sonic Chaos (EB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Sonic Chaos (EB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Sonic Chaos (EB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Sonic Chaos (EB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Aspect</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<family>Sonic</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>1d661134b14eedf6b4ae1c907581fd96</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051405" />
	</game>
	<game id="755">
		<path>./Sonic The Hedgehog (UEB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Sonic the Hedgehog</name>
		<desc>SEGA's mascot Sonic the Hedgehog made his debut in a famous Genesis title, but Sega's 8-bit systems got their own version of the platformer featuring the same story and gameplay style but different levels. To stop the evil Dr. Robotnik, Sonic must traverse six zones consisting of three levels each. Most of the zones are based on the original game, but some are new. Enemies and power-ups are mostly the same as well. Sonic can pick up golden rings for protection (when hit, he simply loses all of his rings instead of a life) and bonuses: 100 rings gain Sonic an extra life, and 50 remaining rings at the end of a level allow access to pinball-themed special stages full of bumpers and springs. The final level of a zone is always a boss fight against Robotnik. Sonic should also collect the six Chaos Emeralds to keep them from falling into Robotnik's hands. In a departure from the original game, these are not hidden in the special stages but somewhere in the regular levels.</desc>
		<image>./images/Sonic The Hedgehog (UEB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Sonic The Hedgehog (UEB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Sonic The Hedgehog (UEB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Sonic The Hedgehog (UEB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Ancient</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<family>Sonic</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>dc13a61eafe75c13c15b5ece419ac57b</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051413" />
	</game>
	<game id="878">
		<path>./Space Harrier (JU) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Space Harrier</name>
		<desc>Run… fly… dodge those obstacles, but return fire on wave after wave of attacking aliens. Armed with a really big gun, you have to defend yourself against the alien hordes using your wits to navigate around the screen. But watch out for those end of level bosses!</desc>
		<image>./images/Space Harrier (JU) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Space Harrier (JU) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Space Harrier (JU) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Space Harrier (JU) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter / TPV</genre>
		<family>Space Harrier</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>b2e5047df186af7c02da17f1b285ae4f</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051418" />
	</game>
	<game id="866">
		<path>./Spider-Man vs. the Kingpin (UEB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Spider-Man</name>
		<desc>The city of New York is certainly a great place to be, but not when there's the criminal element running about. Lucky for the NYPD, there's also the heroic Spider-Man on their side!

But now one of the biggest criminals in the city, Wilson Fisk, a.k.a. The Kingpin, has pulled of the ultimate plot! He announces to New York that a bomb has been planted somewhere in the city, and that it'll go off in 24 hours! What's worse, he lays the blame on Spider-Man, and now the webslinger is on his own, and on the run from the police. Spidey smells a rat, and he knows what he must do.

Spidey has 24 hours to find and disarm that bomb. And he must also clear his name, so he takes his camera to take convincing photos for his Spider-Man hating boss, J. Jonah Jameson, and the police, to prove his innocence. Along the way, he just may run into a few of his *AHEM* "old friends", including Dr. Octopus, Electro, Mysterio, and ultimately Kingpin himself!</desc>
		<image>./images/Spider-Man vs. the Kingpin (UEB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Spider-Man vs. the Kingpin (UEB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Spider-Man vs. the Kingpin (UEB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Spider-Man vs. the Kingpin (UEB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Technopop</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<family>Marvel</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>fa10ee70e43385e88e5d1a008716668b</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051422" />
	</game>
	<game id="836">
		<path>./Taz-Mania (EB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Taz-mania</name>
		<desc>One evening, Taz's father is telling an intriguing tale. Somewhere on Tazmania is a Lost Valley, and in that valley nests a huge seabird, so huge that one of it's eggs could feed a family for a year! Just think of the omelette one of those could make!

Thus Taz becomes fascinated and leaves in search of one of those eggs before his Dad has even finished the story...

Taz can Jump, perform a Spinning Jump and a Spin Attack. Munch roast chickens to replenish life. Gain extra points by moving quickly through the levels - there are six stages and each stage has two rounds.

There are a few other items and pickups such as:

1. Spring: boings Taz up to high ledges.
2. Blocks: destructible.
3. 1-UP: extra life.
4. Star: invulnerability. Unless you run into a bomb.
5. Bomb: does what it says on the tin.</desc>
		<image>./images/Taz-Mania (EB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Taz-Mania (EB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Taz-Mania (EB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Taz-Mania (EB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.6</rating>
		<releasedate>19930201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<family>Looney Tunes</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>cfc878f0163933fcfcc89e134fbeb31f</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051428" />
	</game>
	<game id="758">
		<path>./Wonder Boy III - The Dragon's Trap (UEK) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Wonder Boy III : The Dragon's Trap</name>
		<desc>Wonder Boy III: The Dragon's Trap is a direct sequel to Wonder Boy in Monster Land. When Tom-Tom defeats the MEKA dragon, the wounded beast casts a spell on him, turning him into a Lizard-Man. To regain your original human form, you have to find the Salamander Cross, hidden by the Vampire Dragon in Monster Land.

In this side-scrolling platform game, you can still buy equipment and items, but unlike its predecessor, it is not divided in sequences of levels. You are allowed to go anywhere, as long as you have the right shape or equipment. During his quest, Tom-Tom has to defeat various dragon bosses. Each win will give you a new shape with new abilities such as flying, swimming, walking on ceilings or clinging to walls, which also give you to access new parts of the world. The possible shapes are Lizard-Man, Mouse-Man, Piranha-Man, Lion-Man and Hawk-Man and the main abilities are defined by attacking power, defense points and charm points (needed for equipment by collecting charm stones). Also, certain blocks can only be destroyed by specific weapons or are only accessible to certain shapes.

The basic actions consist of attacking and jumping, and in the status screen you can equip swords, shields and armour. Special attacks include fire balls, tornadoes, arrows, boomerangs and thunder strikes. Along the way, you collect keys (only one at all times) and gold left behind by defeated creatures, and you often have to revisit places to access new areas. A password is given at the beginning of each town to continue from there.</desc>
		<image>./images/Wonder Boy III - The Dragon's Trap (UEK) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Wonder Boy III - The Dragon's Trap (UEK) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Wonder Boy III - The Dragon's Trap (UEK) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Wonder Boy III - The Dragon's Trap (UEK) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19890901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Westone</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<family>Wonder Boy</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<md5>e7f86c049e4bd8b26844ff62bd067d57</md5>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051437" />
	</game>
	<game id="759">
		<path>./Castle of Illusion Starring Mickey Mouse (U) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Castle of Illusion Starring Mickey Mouse</name>
		<desc>Sega's 8-bit systems received their own version of the Genesis' popular Disney platformer. Story and themes remain the same, but the game has unique levels and slightly different gameplay mechanics.

To save his girlfriend Minnie from the evil witch Mizrabel, Mickey Mouse must venture into the Castle of Illusion. Crossing six levels (including a magical forest, a toy land and a candy world), he must collect the gems of the rainbow in order to confront and defeat the witch.

Each level features unique obstacles, enemies and a final boss. The enemies can be defeated by jumping on top of them. An alternative way is to pick up objects lying around (like rocks in the forest or blue balls in the toy level) and throwing them at the enemies. Mickey's ability to pick up things and carry them around also leads to puzzle-oriented gameplay. By placing objects in the right spot and jumping off of them, he can get to areas otherwise out of reach. In some levels, he also has to collect keys to open doors. A unique type of object is the treasure chest - by jumping on top of one or throwing it, Mickey gets access to its contents, which might include extra lives, a health power-up or coins to collect for points.</desc>
		<image>./images/Castle of Illusion Starring Mickey Mouse (U) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/Castle of Illusion Starring Mickey Mouse (U) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/Castle of Illusion Starring Mickey Mouse (U) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/Castle of Illusion Starring Mickey Mouse (U) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19910201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform / Run &amp; Jump Scrolling</genre>
		<family>Disney</family>
		<players>1</players>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20250812T100818</lastplayed>
		<md5>e9b4b92bc29ca8fbe9978da6720bd1eb</md5>
		<gametime>41</gametime>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<region>us</region>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051220" />
	</game>
	<game id="805">
		<path>./TransBot (UEB) [!].sms</path>
		<name>Transbot</name>
		<desc>Back in the solar year 2000 there was a nuclear war, and people are finally now emerging from underground to build a new society. But something is still wrong. DALAUS, a leftover computer from the old world is creating its own empire, and it is up to you to stop it. To complete this mission you will pilot a CA-214 (the TransBot), a new experimental astro-plane. TransBot is a side scrolling shooter for one or two players. There are a wide variety of enemies you will need to get past to be victorious throughout the many locations. The CA-214 can have different types of weapons to help out. You start out with a basic, default gun, but after collection a ? symbol you can choose a new weapon to use. There are six choices which will scroll past at the top of the screen, and your TransBot will be powered with whatever selection you make. Powered up weapons will only last for a limited amount of time before the TransBot reverts back to the basic weapon.</desc>
		<image>./images/TransBot (UEB) [!]-image.png</image>
		<video>./videos/TransBot (UEB) [!]-video.mp4</video>
		<marquee>./images/TransBot (UEB) [!]-marquee.png</marquee>
		<thumbnail>./images/TransBot (UEB) [!]-thumb.png</thumbnail>
		<rating>0.65</rating>
		<releasedate>19861001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
		<playcount>5</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20250921T125402</lastplayed>
		<md5>93bb1e1ee14ac53adb9e6b9e0c135043</md5>
		<gametime>899</gametime>
		<lang>en</lang>
		<scrap name="ScreenScraper" date="20250811T051433" />
	</game>
</gameList>
